Hello! I'm Eje Nathaniel

WEB DEVELOPER || GRAPHICS DESIGNER

www.nathaniel.eu5.org

S3/13, HUDCO QUARTERS NORTH BANK, MAKURDI BENUE STATE

(+234)08103872283 || EJE.NATHANIEL@GMAIL.COM

LINKEDIN: @EJE-NATHANIEL-82047790 || TWITTER: @EJE_NATHANIEL



OBJECTIVE |

I am a web developer and a full blown graphics designer. I am passionate about web design, development and interaction. I am a developer and teacher with experience of working on a variety of web development projects. I work on all aspects of the development life cycle, applying my knowledge of OO PHP and MVC principles. My past work includes building user-focused, dynamic, innovative and functional websites using responsive / adaptive / mobile-first design and development. I have good knowledge of HTML, CSS, SCSS Javascript, ReactJs Bootstrap, WordPress, a bit of Laravel, PHP, and MYSQL.

KEY PROJECTS |

I developed a weather forecast system that consumes an API (application programming interphase) to forecast the current weather of any location in the world. This then tackled manual way of forecast, with a high level of automation, saving an employer the cost of hiring individuals for this.

I developed a portfolio website all from scratch with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and PHP8. This website showcases all of my profile, skills, educational background and qualifications, work experience, services and more; giving anyone anywhere the ability to know about me.

I developed EasyBaby; an application that gives couples choice to choose the sex of a child before conception, know its blood group and genotype, its expected delivery date plus the woman's fertile periods. This helps to cub the issues of conception and choice for a particular gender for a child.

I have also designed graphic for so many clients ranging from banners to posters, invitation and wedding cards and many more.

More about my projects can be found on my website as given at the top of this resume.

KEY SKILLS ||

PHP, Laravel, MySQL

Ability to develop and maintain front and back-

- OOP and MVC principles
- Intermediate in Javascript
- Proficient in HTML and CSS
- CMS –, Wordpress
- Version Control Git
- Bootstrap
- SASS/SCSS
- Experience of building and integrating with API

- end code to a high standard and to agreed timescales
- Ability to review other developers' solutions and code
- Ability to provide clear regular progress updates to managers and stakeholders
- Ability to produce comprehensive documentation
- Able to act as first-line technical support for issues and bugs

QUALIFICATIONS |

BSC (HONS) COMPUTER SCIENCE (2:1)

UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE, 2015-2019

Modules covered included Artificial Intelligence, Data Structures and Algorithms, Logic and Computation, Object Oriented Programming, Full Stack Application Development, Human-Computer Interaction, Intelligent Robotics, Machine Learning and Intelligent Data Analysis, Security of Real-World Systems and Theoretical Foundations for Security.

WORK EXPERIENCE |

WEB DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

ZOE INFOTECH, MAKURDI : APR 2016 – AUG 2016

Here I work under the guidance of experience software engineers - midlevel and senior engineers. My job duties include;

- Coding and debugging of software applications
- Experimenting with design elements
- · Review other engineers' codes
- · Test software applications and patches
- Implement and update software when necessary

I learnt as much as I could about software development as well as learn how to navigate the politics and dynamics of a cooperate or start up setting.

WEB DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

XTECH GLOBAL SERVICES, MAKURDI : APR 2017 – AUG 2018

My role at this company was to assist with supporting software systems, develop new features / projects, and provide occasional hardware support. Part of an in-house team, my responsibilities also included:

- Diagnosing and fixing bugs
- Scoping out and developing new features in line with a specification and to a deadline
- Providing occasional hardware support
- Making improvements to Interfaces and adding new features

FREELANCE FIRVER: JAN 2019 – DATE

Working for different clients, I was responsible for scoping, estimating and testing websites and web-based software for clients. Working as part of a team, I created, developed and finalised projects, many of which were used on a day-to-day by lots of people. I worked closely with different teams and friends; including design, project management and sales to ensure the end result were perfect for the client.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS |

- Coding
- Reading and studying

- Swimming
- Religion am a proud Catholic

REFERENCES ||

Dr. Simon Yange
Department of Mathematics, Statistics and
Computer Science,
University of Agriculture Makurdi
Mobile: +234 (0) 8064067803

Mr Achir Jarome
Department of Mathematics, Statistics and Computer
Science,
University of Agriculture Makurdi
Mobile: +234 (0) 7037839080

Officer E.U Eden (SRC) FRSC National Headquaters, Federal Road Safety Corps (FRSC), Mobile: +234 (0) 8033245158

Let's connect!

www.nathaniel.eu5.org